outdoorandcountry.co.uk 2013-06-28

# Outdoor & Country: Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our Terms of Use and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act), the data controller is Smith and Morris Retail Limited T/A The Outdoor and Country Store of The Old School, Stone Road, Blackbrook, Newcastle-under-Lyme, Staffordshire, ST5 5EG.

Our nominated representative for the purpose of the Act is Jonathan Capener.

### INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU 

You do not have to register to view most of our website. However, some personal information is required if you choose to place an order, contact us via email or request a catalogue. 

We may collect and process the following data about you: 

  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence. 
  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them. 
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our site and of the fulfilment of your orders. 
  * Details of your visits to our site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access. 
  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our site www.OutdoorAndCountry.co.uk (our site). This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our site, subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you enter a competition or promotion sponsored by Smith and Morris Retail Limited T/A The Outdoor and Country Store, and when you report a problem with our site.

### IP ADDRESSES AND COOKIES

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual. 

## About Cookies

### Cookies, what are they and how do they affect me?

A cookie is a piece of information stored in a tiny text file and placed on a visitors’ PC, phone or other web enabled device when they visit our website. They are not harmful and do not contain any confidential information such as address, date of birth or credit card details. The information a cookie contains is set by the server and it can used by that server every time a user visits our site. It can be thought of a way to identify your browser with us. Personal data is not stored within a cookie. They are used for tracking and basic functions such as the shopping basket on our site.

By using our site, you also consent to the use of these cookies.

### Types of cookies we use

We have defined our cookies in three types, tracking cookies, functionality cookies and crucial cookies.

Tracking cookies are used to track user activity across our site.

Functionality cookies are there to ensure certain functions on our site work correctly.

Crucial cookies are essential to perform the basic functions on our site.

### Cookies list

**Cookie Name** | **Party** | **Type** | **Expiration** | **Description**  
---|---|---|---|---  
__utma | Google | Tracking | 2 years | This cookie is used to give each unique browser visit an ID. This enables us to track unique browser and therefore track customer visits to our site.  
__utmb | Google | Tracking | 30 minutes | This cookie is used to establish a session along with __utmc.  
__utmc | Google | Tracking | Not set | This cookie is used to establish a session along with __utmb.  
__utmz | Google | Tracking | 6 months | This cookie is used to track how you got to our site. For example via a search engine.  
SliBeacon_ | Sli Systems | Functionality | 2 years | This cookie is used for our site search analytics, and to improve the relevance of search results for visitors.  
SLI_4 | Sli Systems | Functionality | 6 Months | This cookie is used for our site search analytics, and to improve the relevance of search results for visitors.  
__atuvc | Addthis.com | Functionality | 2 years | This cookie is used by addthis.com who provide our social media plug-in. It allows the visitor to view information such as number of Facebook likes.  
ASP.NET_SessionID | Barbour By Mail | Crucial | Session cookie | This cookie is essential and links visitor browser session to our servers so we can store basket information, process orders and hold recently viewed items.  
ysm_* | Yahoo | Tracking | Session cookie | This cookie is used by Yahoo to track search marketing from the Yahoo search engine.  
  
### How to turn off cookies?

The majority of browsers automatically accept cookies. Should you wish to restrict the cookies we recommend disabling them from within your browser. For more information please visit the help section within your browser.

For more information please see <http://www.aboutcookies.org/>

Please note that our advertisers and tracking software may also use cookies (third-party), over which we have no control.

### WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted (using SSL technology). Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Athough we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

### USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION 

We use information held about you in the following ways: 

  * To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer. 
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes. 
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us. 
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so. 
  * To notify you about changes to our service.

If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale to you.

If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this. If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data (the order form).

### DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION

We do not pass on your details to any third party unless you give us permission to do so notwithstanding the following exceptions: 

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 736 of the UK Companies Act 1985.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties: 

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets. 

  * If Smith and Morris Retail Limited or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets. 
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms of Use or Terms and Conditions of Supply and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Smith and Morris Retail T/A The Outdoor and Country Store, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

### YOUR RIGHTS

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at The Old School, Stone Road, Blackbrook, Newcastle-under-Lyme, Staffordshire, ST5 5EG or [enquiries@OutdoorAndCountry.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@OutdoorAndCountry.co.uk)

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### ACCESS TO INFORMATION 

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. We will provide you with a readable copy of the personal data that we keep about you within 15 working days. There is no charge for this, but evidence of proof of your identity will be required.

It is in our interest and yours to hold accurate date. If the data we hold on you is inaccurate in any way where appropriate you may have the data: erased; rectified or amended; completed.

###  CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY 

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

### DISPUTE 

We aim to ensure that we have resolved any matters satisfactorily, however if you are not satisfied with our response you may contact: 

The Information Commissioner  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF

Telephone: 01625 545 700   
Fax: 01625 524 510   
DX: 20819 Wilmslow   
Email: [mail@dataprotection.gov.uk](mailto:mail@dataprotection.gov.uk)   
Website: [http://www.dataprotection.gov.uk](http://www.dataprotection.gov.uk/)

### CONTACT

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to our Customer Service team at [enquiries@OutdoorAndCountry.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@OutdoorAndCountry.co.uk) or: 

The Outdoor & Country Store  
The Old School  
Stone Road  
Blackbrook  
Newcastle-under-Lyme  
Staffordshire  
ST5 5EG 

Or telephone: 0844 844 8998
